Guide to the William A. Speck Collection of Prints
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
William A. Speck collection of prints.
1750-1850
YCGL MSS 11
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
38.77
(42 boxes) + 13 broadside drawers
Print collection of portraits, views, and illustrations focused on Johann Wolfgang von Goethe. The portraits are of persons associated with Goethe, and include an extensive file on Goethe. The views are of places where Goethe lived or visited, particularly Weimar, and the illustrations are of scenes and characters from Goethe's works.
Speck, William A. (William Alfred), 1864-1928
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was built by the library by gift and purchase from various sources. These include a core group of prints collected by William A. Speck and brought to Yale when he accepted the position of curator of the Yale Collection of German Literature; items purchased for the collection with Yale funds by Speck, including approximately 3750 prints from the Berg Collection, or received as gifts during his tenure; and materials acquired since by the library, by gift or purchase.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The William A. Speck Collection of Prints contains portraits, views and illustrations documenting the life, work, and reception of Johann Wolfgang von Goethe. The collection is housed in 42 boxes, plus numerous broadside folders, and consists of three series: Portraits, Views, and Illustrations. While most of the collection is composed of prints, other formats may also be found, including watercolors, silhouettes, printed ephemera, and a few photographs.
Series I, Portraits is arranged alphabetically by name. Series II, Views is arranged by country, and within that by city. It should be noted that the place names in Series II are those that were in use in the 1920s and 30s, when most of the collection was cataloged, and therefore may not reflect current usage or political divisions.
The Portraits series includes portraits of Goethe and of his associates, but also includes many contemporaries not closely associated with the poet. The Views and Illustrations focus more narrowly on Goethe himself, his life and work, depicting places where Goethe lived or visited, or which he discussed in his works, particularly Weimar, and scenes and characters from Goethe's works, in particular Faust.
In addition to this listing, which was compiled by labeling on the files, a card index exists in the curator's office, which provides access by artist name to many, though probably not all, works encompassed in this collection. These cards also may contain additional information, including such things as names of engraver, place of creation, date of creation, and bibliographic citations. For further information about the card index, consult the appropriate curator.
Germans -- Portraits; Germany -- Pictorial works; Weimar (Germany) -- Pictorial works; Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von, 1749-1832 -- Portraits; Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von, 1749-1832 ( Faust, Illustrations)
- Portraits, Series I; 5; (12 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Portraits is arranged alphabetically.
  - "A"
    - Abel, E. H. (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Abt, Felicitas, 1746-1782 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Ackermann, Frau (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Alton (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Ammon, Christoph Friedrich von, 1766-1850 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - André, Johann, 1741-1799 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Anna Amalia, Duchess of Saxe-Weimar-Eisenach, 1739-1807 (Box 1, Folder ++)
    - Arnim, Bettina Brentano von, 1785-1859 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - August, prince of Saxe-Gotha and Altenburg, 1747-1806 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - August Ferdinand von Veltheim (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Auguste, Duchess of Braunschweig, 1737-1813 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - "B"
    - Baden, Amalie Friederike Margkgräfin von, 1754-1832 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Bagration, Katharina Fürstine (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Bahrdt, Karl Friedrich, 1741-1792 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Bardua, Caroline, 1781-1864 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Basedow, Johann Bernhard, 1723-1790 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Bassenheim, Johann Maria Rudolf, Reichsgraf Walbott von und zu, 1731-1805 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Bause, Johann Friedrich, 1738-1814 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Bause - Family (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Beauharnais, Eugène de, prince d'Eichstätt, 1781-1824 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Beaulieu-Marconnay, Frau Henriette von Egloffstein von, 1773-1864 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Beck, Heinrich, 1760-1803 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Beck, Frau Josepha Schaeffer (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Beck, Luise, 1789-1857 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Berg, Karl, 1851-1922 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Bergmann, Torbern Olof, 1735-1784 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Bertuch, Friedrich Justin, 1747-1822 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Berzelius, Jöns Jakob, friherre, 1779-1848 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Bethmann von - Family (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Birken, Sigmund von (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Bodmer, Johann Jakob, 1698-1783 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Böhme, Jon. Gottlob, 1717-1780 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Böhmer, Auguste, 1785-1800 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Boie, Heinrich Christian, 1744-1806 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Boisserée, Melchior, 1786-1851 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Boisserée, Sulpiz, 1783-1854 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Boettiger, Karl August, 1760-1835 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Born, Jacob Heinrich, 1750-1782 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Bostel, Frau Anna Margareta Dietz von, 1750-1796 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Branconi, Maria Antonia von Elsener Marquise von, 1751-1793 (Box 1, Folder ++)
    - Brandt, Anna (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Breidenbach, Karl Wilh., Freiherr von, 1751-1831 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Breitkopf, Bernhard Christoph, 1695-1777 (Box 1, Folder ++)
    - Breitkopf, Christoph Gottlob, 1750-1800 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Breitkopf, Johann Gottlob Imanuel, 1719-1794 (Box 1, Folder ++)
    - Brentano, Frau Antonia von Birkenstock, 1780-1869 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Brentano, Clemens Maria, 1778-1842 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Brentano, Frau Maximiliane Euphrosyne von La Roche 1756-1793 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Brion, Friederike Elisabeth, 1752-1813 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Brion: family etc. (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Brückner, Frau C. M. Klefelder (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Brückner, Joh. Gottfried, 1730-1786 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Brühl, Carl Friedrich Moritz Paul, Graf von, 1772-1837 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Bürger, Gottfried August, 1747-1794 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Burggrave, Johann Philipp, 1700-1775 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Bury, Friedrich, 1763-1823 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Byron, George Gordon Noël Byron, 6th Baron, 1788-1824 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - "C"
    - Cagliostro, Allessandro, conte di, assumed name of Giuseppe Balsamo, 1743-1795 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Cagliostro - Family (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Carlyle, Thomas, 1795-1881 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Caroline Louise, hereditary grand duchess of Mecklenburg-Schwerin, 1786-1816 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Carus, Karl Gustav, 1789-1869 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Catalini, Angelika (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Cella, Johann Jakob, 1756-1820 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Chodowiecki, Daniel Nikolaus, 1726-1801 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Chodowiecki - Family (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Claudy, Frank, 1844-1919 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Clerfayt, François Sebastian Joseph de Croix (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Clodius, Christian August, 1738-1784 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Clodius - Family (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Colloredo Mannsfeld - Family (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Constantin, prince of Saxe-Weimar (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Conta, Carl Friedrich Anton von, 1778-1850 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Cornelius, Peter von, 1783-1867 (Box 1, Folder ++)
    - Cotta, Johann Friedrich, Freiherr von, 1764-1832 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Coudray, Clemens Wenceslaus, Baumeister, 1775-1845 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Crespel Family (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Cuvier, Frédéric Georges (Box 1, Folder +)
  - "D"
    - Dalberg, Karl Theodor Anton Maria von, 1744-1817 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Dalberg, Wolfgang Heribert von, 1750-1806 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Dannecker, Joh. Heinr., 1758-1841 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - David D'Angers, Pierre Jean, 1788-1856 (Box 1, Folder ++)
    - Devrient, Eduard, 1801-0877 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Döbbelin, Caroline Maximiliane, 1758-1828 (Box 1, Folder ++)
    - Döbbelin, Karl Theophil, 1727-1793 (Box 1, Folder +)
    - Döbereiner, Johann Wolfgang, 1780-1849 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Doré, Frau Fanny Caspers, 1787-1835 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Dumeiz, Friedrich Damian, [ca. 1808] (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Dumouriez, Charles Francois Duperier, 1739-1823 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Durand, Friedrich August Aumann, 1787-1852 (Box 2, Folder +)
  - "E"
    - Eberwein, Karl, 1786-1868 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Eckermann, Johann Peter, 1792-1854 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Egloffstein, Familie von (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Ehrhardt, Georg, 1862- (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Ehrmann, Johann Christian, 1749-1827 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Eichstädt, Hernrich Karl Abraham, 1772-1848 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Einsiedel, Friedrich Hildebrand, Freiherr von, 1750-1828 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Eissl, Frau Therese von Oberndorfer (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Ekhof, Hans Konrad Dietrich, 1720-1778 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Ernesti, Johann August, 1707-1781 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Ernst I, duke of Saxe-Coburg-Gotha (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Ernst II, duke of Saxe-Gotha and Altenburg, 1745-1804 (Box 2, Folder ++)
    - Ernst III, Friedrich Karl, duke of Saxe-Hildburghausen, 1727-1780 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Ernst August, duke of Saxe-Weimar-Eisenach, 1588-1748 (Box 2, Folder ++)
    - Ernst August II, Constantin, duke of Saxe-Weimar-Eisenach, 1737-1758 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Eschenburg, Johann Joachim, 1743-1820 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Ewald, Johann Ludwig, 1747-1822 (Box 2, Folder +)
  - "F"
    - Fäsi, Johann Konrad, 1727-1790 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Ferdinando I, King of the Two Sicilies, 1751-1825 (Box 2, Folder ++)
    - Fernow, Carl Ludwig, 1763-1808 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Fibich, Susanne Cleophe, 1754-1820 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Fichte, Johann Gottlieb, 1762-1814 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Fiedler, Johann Christian, 1697-1765 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Filangieri, Gaetano, 1752-1788 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Finucci, Mrs. Maddalena Riggi Volpato, 1765-1825 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Fischer (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Fochem, Gerhard Kunibert (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Forster, Johann Reinhold, 1729-1798 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Franckenberg, Sylvius Friedrich Ludwig, Freiherr von, 1728-1815 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Franz I, emperor of Austria, 1768-1835 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Franziska Theresia, Countess of Hohenheim, duchess of Wuerttemberg and Teck, 1748-1811 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Friederike Luise, Königin von Preussen (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Friedrich I, King of Württemberg, 1754-1816 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Friedrich II, der Grosse, King of Prussia, 1712-1786 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Friedrich IV, Duke of Saxe-Gotha and Altenburg, 1774-1825 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Friedrich Eugen, Duke of Württemberg, 1732-1797 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Friedrich Karl Joseph, Archbishop and Elector of Mainz, 1719-1802 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Friedrich Wilhelm II, King of Prussia, 1744-1797 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Friesen, Johann Georg Friedrich, Freiherr von, 1757-1824 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Fritsch, Jakob Friedrich, Freiherr von, 1731-1814 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Frommann, Alwine, 1800-1875 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Frommann, Friedrich Johannes, 1797-1886 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Froriep, Ludw. Friedr. von, 1779-1847 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Fürstenberg, Franz Friedrich Wilhelm Maria, Freiherr von, 1729-1810 (Box 2, Folder ++)
  - "G"
    - Gall, Franz Joseph, 1758-1828 (Box 2, Folder ++)
    - Gallitzin, Adelheid Amalie Fürstin Gräfin von Schmettau, 1748-1806 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Garve, Christian, 1742-1798 (Box 2, Folder ++)
    - Geismar, von (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Gellert, Christian Fürchtegott, 1715-1729 (Box 2, Folder ++)
    - Genast, Anton, 1765-1831 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Genast, Eduard Franz, 1796-1866 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Gentz, Friedrich von, 1764-1832 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Georg Friedrich Karl, Duke of Saxe-Coburg-Meiningen, 1761-1803 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Gerning, Johann Isaak von, 1767-1837 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Gessner, Johann Georg, 1765-1843 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Gessner, Salomon, 1730-1788 (Box 2, Folder ++)
    - Giovane, Herzogin Julie von, 1766-1805 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Gleichen-Russwurm, Heinrich Adalbert, Freiherr von, 1803-1887 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Gleichen-Russwurm - Family (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Gleim, Johann Wilhelm Ludwig, 1719-1803 (Box 2, Folder ++)
    - Gmelin, Christian Gottlieb, 1749-1818 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Gmelin, Johann Friedrich, 1748-1804 (Box 2, Folder ++)
    - Göchhausen, Luise Ernestine Christiane Juliane von, 1752-1807 (Box 2, Folder +)
    - Göckingk, Leopold Friedrich Günther von, 1748-1828 (Box 2, Folder ++)
    - Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von
      - Busts - David D'Angers (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Busts - Faltermeier (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Busts - Flatters (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Busts - Klauer (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Busts - Posch (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Busts - Rauch (Box 3, Folder ++)
      - Busts - Schadow (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Busts - Schweigardt (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Busts - Tieck (Box 3, Folder ++)
      - Busts - Trippel (Box 3, Folder ++)
      - Busts - Wagner (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Busts - Weisser (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Busts - 1949 Bronze Bust (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Caricatures (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Masks - Schadow (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Masks - Wiesser (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Medallions - David D'Angers (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Medallions - Angelika Facius (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Medallions - Kügelgen, 1809 (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Medallions - Melchior, 1775 (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Medals - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Medals - Bovy (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Medals - Brandt (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Medals - Angelika Facius (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Medals - König (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Medals - König-Loos, 1826 (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Medals - Loos (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Medals - Schadow (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Miniature - Remde (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Miniature - based on J. K. Stieler's port. (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Monuments - Unidentified (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Monuments - Berlin (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Monuments - Bettina v. Arnim (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Monuments - Brocken Harz (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Monuments - Chicago (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Monuments - Brooklyn (Central Park) Model by Henry Baerer (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Monuments - Frankfurt (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Monuments - Franzensbad (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Monuments - Jena (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Monuments - Kochel am Kochelsee (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Monuments - Leipzig (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Monuments - Marienbad (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Monuments - New York City (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Monuments - Rome (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Monuments - Strassburg (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Monuments - Torbole (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Monuments - Vienna (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Monuments - Weimar (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Monuments - Baerer, Planned for Brooklyn (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Monuments - Flemming (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Monuments - Rauch (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Monuments - Rietschel (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Youth (Box 3, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Old Age (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder ++)
      - Portraits - Anon. ca. 1765 (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Anon. Ein unbekanntes Goethe Bildnis in Züricher Privatbesitz. (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Bager (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Bager - Saiter - Geyser (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Bardua (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Bauer, Charlotte (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Bauer (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Bosse, after 1810 (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Brandt (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Bury (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Collins (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - d'Alton (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Darbes, 1785 (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Dawe, 1819 (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Dawe (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Deveria d'Après David (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Egloffstein (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Fleischer (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Gest (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Goethe (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Graff (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Grünler (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Hackert (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - E. Hader, 1780, 1812 (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Heideloff (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Hensel, Wilh. Zeichnung. Marienbad 1823 (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Fidus - 1899 (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Hothsteiner (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Imhof (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - C. Jäger (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Jagemann (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Juel - 1779 (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - K .F. Kaaz, 1809 (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Kauffmann, 1787 (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Kern, A.J. Ein neuentdecktes Goethebild (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Kihm (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Kolbe (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Kraus (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Kügelgen, 1808/1810 (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Lalauze (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Lips (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Lips-Lavater (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Matthaey (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - O. May (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Melchior, 1779 (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Meyer (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - F. H. Müller (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Oeser (Box 4, Folder ++)
      - Portraits - Pfenninger (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Preller (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Raabe (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Ramberg (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Schadow (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Schmeller - 1826-27 (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Schmeller. Ein unbekanntes Goethe-Bildnis von Joh. Jos. Schmeller sus de Jahre 1829 or 1825? (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Schmoll (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Schönberg-Rothschönberg (Box 4, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Schwerdgeburth (Box 4, Folder ++)
      - Portraits - Sebbers (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Seekatz (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Seidler (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Stieler (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Stieler-Thackeray-Maclise (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Thackeray (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Tischbein (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Vogel von Vogelstein (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Weisser (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Zuber (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Portraits - Gruppenbilder (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Reliefs - Unidentified (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Reliefs - Fischer (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Reliefs - Posch (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Silhouettes - Unidentified (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Silhouettes - Feder (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Silhouettes - 1785- (Box 5, Folder ++)
      - Silhouettes - Anon. (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Silhouettes - Rauch (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Goethe im Bild - Klauer. Goethe und Fritz von Stein (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Goethe im Bild - Kraus (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Goethe im Bild - Reinhart, 1804 (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Goethe im Bild - Seekartz (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Goethe im Bild - Tischbein (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Goethe im Bild - Trautmann (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Goethe im Bild - Unidentified (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Goethe Family - Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Goethe Family - Goethe, Alma Sedina Heriette Cornelia von, 1827-1844 (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Goethe Family - Goethe, August von, 1789-1830 (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Goethe Family - Goethe, Frau Christiane Sophie Vulpius von, 1765-1816 (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Goethe Family - Goethe, Johann Kaspar, 1710-1782 (Box 5, Folder ++)
      - Goethe Family - Goethe, Frau Katherina Elisabeth Textor, 1731-1808 (Box 5, Folder ++)
      - Goethe Family - Goethe, Frau Ottilie von Pogwisch von, 1796-1872 (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Goethe Family - Goethe, Walther Wolfgang, Freiherr von, 1818-1885 (Box 5, Folder ++)
      - Goethe Family - Goethe, Wolfgang Maximilian, Freiherr von, 1820-1883 (Box 5, Folder +)
      - Goethe's Drawings - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder ++)
      - Goethe's Drawings - Bilin (Box 6, Folder +)
      - Goethe's Drawings - Italy (Box 6, Folder +)
      - Goethe's Drawings - Jena (Box 6, Folder +)
      - Goethe's Drawings - Switzerland (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Görres, Johann Josef von, 1776-1848 (Box 6, Folder ++)
    - Göschen, Georg Joachim, 1752-1828 (Box 6, Folder ++)
    - Göttling, Karl Wilhelm, 1793-1869 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Götz, Gottlieb Christian, b. 1758 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Goetze, Johann Georg Paul, 1759-1835 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Goldsmith, Oliver, 1728-1774 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Gontard, Frau Susette Borkenstein, 1769-1802 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Gore, Charles, 1726-1807 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Gotter, Friedrich Wilhelm, 1746-1797 (Box 6, Folder ++)
    - Gotter - Family (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Gottsched, Johann Christoph, 1700-1766 (Box 6, Folder ++)
    - Goué, August Friedrich von, 1743-1789 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Grabmal Des Grafen von Gleichen. Gleichen, Ernst III, Graf von [?] (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Graff, Anton, 1736-1813 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Graff, Johann Jakob, 1768-1848 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Graff - Family (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Gretchen, Goethe's first love (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Griesbach, Johann Jacob (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Grillparzer, Franz, 1791-1872 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Grimm, Friedrich Melchior, Freiherr von, 1723-1807, grave (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Grimm, Jacob Ludwig Karl, 1785-1863 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Grimm, Ludwig Emil, 1790-1863 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Grimm, Wilhelm Karl, 1786-1859 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Grossmann, Gustav Friedrich Wilhelm, 1746-1796 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Grüner, Joseph Sebastian, 1780-1864 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Grüner, Karl Franz d'Akáts, genannt Grümer, 1780-1845 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Guaita, Frau Maria Magdalema Carolina Francisca Brentano, 1788-1861 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Günderode, Karoline Friederike Maximiliane von, 1780-1806 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Gundelfinger, Friedrich, 1880- (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Gusted, Jenny von Pappenheim Frei-in von, 1811-1890 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Gutzkow, Karl Ferdinand, 1811-1878 (Box 6, Folder +)
  - "H"
    - Hackert, Jacob Philipp, 1737-1807 (Box 6, Folder ++)
    - Haefeli, Johann Kaspar, 1754-1811 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Haffner, Isaak, 1751-1836 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Hagedorn, Christian Ludwig von, 1712-1780 (Box 6, Folder ++)
    - Haide, Friedrich J.M.J., 1771-1832 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Hamilton, Emma Lyon Lady, 1761?-1815 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Hamilton, Sir William, 1730-1803 (Box 6, Folder ++)
    - Hardenberg, Friedrich Leopold, Freiherr von, 1772-1801 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Hardenberg, Karl August, Fürst von, 1750-1822 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Hartmann Seelsorger (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Hauptmann, Gerhart Robert Johann, 1862- (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Hauptmann, Frau Pauline Anna Milder, 1785-1838 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Hebel, Jonann Peter, 1760-1826 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Heideloff, Carl Alexander, 1788-1865 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Heine, Heinrich (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Heinrich i.e. Friedrich Heinrich Ludwig, prince of Prussia, 1726-1802 (Box 6, Folder +)
    - Heinrich VIII, Fürst Reuss ä.L. (Box 6, Folder +)